

Ruhollah Taghizadeh

POSTDOC RESEARCHER

Department of Geosciences, University of Tübingen

☑ruhollah.taghizadeh-mehrjardi@mnf.uni-tuebingen.de | ☆ruhollahtaghizadeh.netlify.app | ☑RuhollahTaghizadeh | ☑RuhollahTaghizadeh | ☑RuhollahTaghiz

About me_

My primary research interest is in **Pedometrics** with a particular focus on **Digital Soil Mapping**. The core of the pedometric approach integrates soil system knowledge with advanced statistical methods, **Machine Learning**, geoinformatics, and **Remote Sensing**. I apply the most recent technology in spatial data analysis to model and predict various environmental metrics such as soils, water, vegetation, and climate.

Experience	
Department of Geosciences, University of Tübingen, Germany Postdoc Researcher	2017-Present
Department of Plant Science, South Dakota State University, USA Postdoc Researcher	2016
Faculty of Agriculture, Ardakan University, Iran Assistant Professor	2013-2017
Department of Soil and Water, Agricultural Research Center, Iran Geospatial Consultant	2010-2011
Education	
Faculty of Agricultural Engineering and Technology, University of Tehran, Iran Doctor of Philosophy in Agricultural Engineering-Soil Science	2012
Sydney Institute of Agriculture, The University of Sydney, Australia Postgraduate Visiting Scholar in Digital Soil Mapping	2012
Faculty of Agricultural Engineering and Technology, University of Tehran, Iran Master of Science in Agricultural Engineering-Soil Science	2008
Faculty of Agriculture, SB University of Kerman, Iran Bachelor of Science in Agricultural Engineering-Soil Science	2005
Projects	
German Research Foundation Sensitivity and Response of Himalayan Timberline Ecotones to Global Warming (Collaborator)	2022
German Research Foundation Transferability of Machine Learning for Soil Mapping (Collaborator)	2020
Iranian Agricultural Research, Education & Extension Organization Digital Soil Mapping in Kurdistan (Collaborator)	2019
Alexander von Humboldt Foundation Digital Soil Mapping with Limited Data (Principal Investigator)	2017

Research Interests

Pedology; Digital Soil Mapping; Remote and Proximal Sensing; Spatial Data Analysis; Machine Learning; Statistical Inference; Soil Health; Climate Change; Precision Agriculture

Teaching Assistant at University of Tübingen, Germany	2020-Present
- Spatial Pedology and Geomorphology 🏶	GS
- Statistics 🏶	UGS
Workshop Lecturer	2013-Presen
- An introduction to Spatial Analysis in QGIS, University of Tübingen	2 hrs2022
- An introduction to GIS, University of Tübingen	2 hrs2022
- Spatial Data in R, Iranian Soil & Water Research Institute 🏶	7 days online-2022
- Digital Soil Mapping in R, Iranian Soil & Water Research Institute	2 days-2016
- Data Mining in Soil Sciences, Iranian Soil & Water Research Institute	2 days-2016
Fellowships, Honors, Awards	
Five Nominated Pedometrics Best Paper	2020
Alexander von Humboldt Postdoctoral Fellowship	2017
Lecturer Award at Ardakan University	2017
Professional Services	
Award Committee Member of the Pedometrics Commission	2022-Present
Executive Board Member of International Soil Modeling Consortium	2022-Presen
Associate Editor of Frontiers in Soil Science/Pedometrics	2022-Presen
Webmaster of Pedometrics Homepage	2022-Presen
Professional Training	
Open Source Solutions for Earth System Data, OpenGeoHub	2022
Oxford Machine Learning Summer School, AI for Global Goals	2022
Science Communication, University of Tübingen	2022
Agile Project Management for Research, University of Tübingen	2022
Spatial Sampling, Wageningen University & Research Leading Virtual Teams, University of Tübingen	2021 2021
Uncertainty Propagation in Spatial Modelling, Wageningen University & Research	202.
Geostatistics, Wageningen University & Research	2019
GEOSTAT Summer School, OpenGeoHub	2018
Digital Soil Mapping, ISRIC	2018
Digital Soil Mapping with R, The University of Sydney	2012
Technical Skills	
Programming	
- R	***
- R Markdown	
- Python Spatial Data Analysis	
- QGIS	***
- ArcMap	***
- SAGA GIS	****
- Google Earth Engine	***
Office	
- Word, Excel, PowerPoint	***
Soil Science	
- Digital Soil mapping	***
- Soil Chemical and Physical Analysis	***
- Soil Mineralogical and Micromorphological Analysis	***
- Description, Classification and Interpretation of Soils in the Field	***

Field Work _____

Soil Sampling, Soil Survey, Geophysical Surveys, Soil Erosion Surveys	Iran
Soil Sampling, Soil Survey, Land Evaluation	Kenya
Soil Sampling	USA

Research Impacts.

•	
Publications	
Peer Reviewed Journals	85
- First Author	21
- Co-First Author	3
- Last Author	17
- Corresponding Author	25
Book Chapters	3
Book Editor (in Persian)	1
Presentations	17
H-Index	
Google Scholar	28
Scopus	25
Web of Science	24
Web of Science	24
Citation	
Google Scholar	2692
Scopus	2006
Web of Science	1769

Publications

SELECTED PAPERS (* INDICATES CORRESPONDING AUTHOR)

- 1. **Taghizadeh-Mehrjardi, R.***; Sheikhpour, R.; Zeraatpisheh, M.; Amirian-Chakan, A.; Toomanian, N.; Kerry, R.; Scholten, T. *Semi-Supervised Learning for the Spatial Extrapolation of Soil Information*. Geoderma 2022, 426, 116094, doi:10.1016/j.geoderma.2022.116094.
- 2. **Taghizadeh-Mehrjardi, R.***; Schmidt, K.; Toomanian, N.; Heung, B.; Behrens, T.; Mosavi, A.; S. Band, S.; Amirian-Chakan, A.; Fathabadi, A.; Scholten, T. *Improving the Spatial Prediction of Soil Salinity in Arid Regions Using Wavelet Transformation and Support Vector Regression Models*. Geoderma 2021, 383, 114793, doi:10.1016/j.geoderma.2020.114793.
- 3. **Taghizadeh-Mehrjardi, R.**; Hamzehpour, N.; Hassanzadeh, M.; Heung, B.; Ghebleh Goydaragh, M.; Schmidt, K.; Scholten, T. *Enhancing the Accuracy of Machine Learning Models Using the Super Learner Technique in Digital Soil Mapping*. Geoderma 2021, 399, 115108, doi:10.1016/j.geoderma.2021.115108.
- 4. **Taghizadeh-Mehrjardi, R.***; Mahdianpari, M.; Mohammadimanesh, F.; Behrens, T.; Toomanian, N.; Scholten, T.; Schmidt, K. *Multi-Task Convolutional Neural Networks Outperformed Random Forest for Mapping Soil Particle Size Fractions in Central Iran*. Geoderma 2020, 376, 114552, doi:10.1016/j.geoderma.2020.114552.
- 5. **Taghizadeh-Mehrjardi, R.***; Nabiollahi, K.; Minasny, B.; Triantafilis, J. *Comparing Data Mining Classifiers to Predict Spatial Distribution of USDA-Family Soil Groups in Baneh Region, Iran*. Geoderma 2015, 253–254, 67–77, doi:10.1016/j.geoderma.2015.04.008.

All Papers → Google Scholar and ResearchGate